<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robustness Dashboard</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Robustness Dashboard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A 12-min talk</title>
      <link>/post/a-short-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-short-talk/</guid>
      <description>In an online workshop on the theme of “COVID-19 and Public Policy and Management” (May 1st) at Arizona State Unviersity, Prof. Spiro Maroulis gave a talk “Communicating the Robustness of Inferences as COVID-19 Evidence Accumulates.” See the link here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HCQ</title>
      <link>/post/hcq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hcq/</guid>
      <description>Since we have a \(2 \times2\) table, we use tkonfound function to calculates the number of cases (RIS) that would have to be switched from one cell to another of a \(2 \times2\) table to invalidate an inference made about the association between the rows and columns. This can be applied to treatment vs control with successful vs unsuccessful outcomes.
konfound::tkonfound(a = 14, b = 17, c = 6, d= 25) ## [[1]] ## [1] &amp;quot;The tkonfound function calculates the number of cases that would have to be switched from one cell to another of a 2x2 table to invalidate an inference made about the association between the rows and columns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remdesivir</title>
      <link>/post/remdesivir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/remdesivir/</guid>
      <description>konfound: Remdesivir on mortality konfound::tkonfound(a = 10, b = 68, c = 22, d= 136) ## [[1]] ## [1] &amp;quot;The tkonfound function calculates the number of cases that would have to be switched from one cell to another of a 2x2 table to invalidate an inference made about the association between the rows and columns. This can be applied to treatment vs control with successful vs unsuccessful outcomes.&amp;quot; ## ## [[2]] ## [1] &amp;quot;See konfound_fig for full and accessible details in graphic form!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>We are a group of researchers who would like to contribute to
It makes use of a variety of open source projects including:
 Cobra Viper J Walter Weatherman Cast  Learn more and contribute on GitHub.
Setup Some fun facts about Hugo:
 Built in Go Loosely inspired by Jekyll Primarily developed by spf13 on the train while commuting to and from Manhattan. Coded in Vim using spf13-vim  Have questions or suggestions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Have a question about R, KonFound-it, or us? Want to collaborate for a certain project? Do not hesitate to contact us. We prefer messages and questions via email.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>